Joe Durbridge

Email jdurbridge@me.com • Mobile 07977 449 081

PROFILE

Experienced Marketing Senior Account Manager (B2B and B2C)

I am currently a Senior Account Manager, working across several retail clients and brands, including IKEA, Karcher, Portus and AEG, within a full-service marketing agency. I've worked across an array of marketing channels delivering successful campaigns and helping brands grow.

ACADEMIC

MA International Events Management & Marketing (2008-2009)

University of Brighton

EMPLOYMENT

BWP Group | Senior Account Manager (2018 - present)

In my current role I service IKEA working in partnership with other agencies, to deliver brand and tactical level campaigns across the UK and ROI. I also support ICON shopping Outlet at The O2 with digital marketing and I'm overseeing a day to marketing for a shopping centre in Brussels. Working with my Account Executive, I oversee a collection of lower-tier clients who I've had long-term relationships with spanning 4-5 years.

BWP Group | Campaign Manager (2017 - 2018)

I was asked to take on the role of campaign manager and create a social media department to service seven client's social media accounts. The role required me to put processes in place, create strategies and integrate our content, accounts and creative teams. I've also worked on influencer programs, social campaign development and paid social media campaigns.

BWP Group | Account Manager (2016 - 2017)

As an account manager, I was the key point of contact for many tier one and tier two accounts, including O2 and British Gas b2b departments. My role was to act as the engine of the account group, fully responsible for driving the effective delivery of client projects and marketing plans, on time and budget.

BWP Group | Senior Account Executive (2014 - 2016)

Working as part of the B2B team within an integrated agency, my role was to support the account team, assist my account manager across a range of marketing disciplines.

Scorpion Group | Operations Manager (2009 - 2014)

Before my career in marketing I worked in hospitality for ten years in the capacity of General then Operations manager, managing bars, restaurants and a boutique hotel. At Scorpion Group, I looked after high-end venues overseeing all commercial aspects of the business, including the business strategy, purchasing, recruitment & training and marketing. I worked closely with a specialist hospitality marketing agency and in collaboration with them, developed and executed a group marketing strategy. I managed up to fifty staff, developed robust training plans and closely mentored assistant managers who all went on to become successful general managers.

MARKETING EXPERIENCE (Snapshot)

- Print and digital creative
- Google Adwords and PPC campaigns
- Website management
- CRM and email campaign design
- Print media and media buying
- Web design, UX planning and SEO
- Content marketing and social media
- Analytics and reporting

ACCOUNT MANAGEMENT SKILLS

- Competent user of Microsoft office
- Effective communication and people skills
- Problem solving and brief writing
- Financial control and budgeting
- Time management and organisation
- Project management and processes
- Excellent attention to detail and diligence
- Good comprehension of strategy and tactics

Joe Durbridge

Page 2:

COMPETENCIES

A people person

Confident, self-assured, capable and able to build effective warm and engaging relationships quickly, both internally and externally with clients and suppliers alike. Comfortable challenging colleagues and clients positively with alternative ideas and developing trust through effective partnerships.

A big picture person

Able to see a brand's perspective, appreciating the wider context and commercial opportunities both for the agency and for the client. An ability to think creatively around commercial opportunities.

A details person

Comfortable working within standard processes and procedures with clear time guidelines. An ethos that attention to detail is key to ensure an effective and efficient delivery of work.

A numbers person

Good with figures, spreadsheets, managing turnover, margins, forecasting, perceived value for money, and delivering against client ROIs and agency targets.

A marketing person

A love for marketing and the challenge of solving a problem through effective communication and creativity. The process and journey with the clients and successful campaigns are always the most rewarding aspect of marketing.

TRAINING

Mini MBA Marketing

I undertook the 12-week mini MBA delivered by professor Mark Ritson and Marketing Week. The MW Mini MBA in Marketing is a CPD accredited, MBA level course. Covering the same content and theories as the marketing core class taught on MBA programmes at the top business schools.

MAA Excellence in Account Management

An intensive two-and-a-half-day training course aimed at Account Manager level focusing on developing and expanding the wider range of skills required day to day at Account Manager level.

REFERENCES

Available upon request